ARAF AL-JAMI

 $arafaljami1331@gmail.com \diamond araf.aljami.me \diamond +8801755045141$

SUMMARY

Around 2 years of working experience as a software engineer, with a strong pursuit of problem solving. Hands on experience in building enterprise applications and maintaining best practices with OOD. Followed SOLID principles and design patterns to write clean, maintainable and adaptive code.

SKILLS

Languages: C#, Typescript, Javascript, C/C++

Specialties: .NET, .NET Core, Web API, Git, Git Flow, IdentityServer4, Agile Scrum methodology, Angular Database and messaging: MongoDB, EF Core, MySQL, MassTransit, RabbitMQ, Mqtt, Azure Service Bus.

EXPERIENCE

Shohoj Limited, Dhaka

Feb 2020 - Present

Software Engineer, Platform

- · Used Dotnet Core technologies to develop REST API.
- · Used **S2Geometry**, **Redis** to refine the Nearest provider search.
- · Used IdentityServer4 to implement identity access management service.
- · Used **TDD**, **DDD** to write robust, adaptable code.
- · Worked on Shohoz Review Service, a tenant aware review rating service on scale.
- · Worked on Corona Tracer BD, contact tracing application for Bangladesh.

SELISE rockin' software, Dhaka

Nov 2018 - Jan 2020

Software Engineer

- · Used Angular, Angular S to develop Single Page Applications
- · Used Dotnet Core technologies to develop REST API.
- · Worked on multiple projects and implemented business requirements for Selise Auditing and Certification Platform.

Problem Setter and Judge at NSU Cybernauts National Programming Contest 2019

· Set problem and written alternate solution. [link]

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

Onsite Competitive Programming Contests

September 2014 - Present

- \cdot 10th place (4th place University wise) out of **150** teams, at IUBAT ACM NCPC 2018. [link]
- · 16th place (8th place University wise) out of **120** teams, at MIST IUPC 2019

Online Competitive Programming Contests

September 2014 - Present

- · Active participant in online coding challenges on sites such as **TopCoder**, **Codeforces**.
- · Achieved Maximum Rating of 1982 (top 4%) in Codeforces. Handle: CLown1331. [link]
- · Achieved Maximum Rating of 1469 (Division 1) in TopCoder. Handle: CLown1331. [link]
- · Solved around 2800 problems in various online judges. [link]

EDUCATION

Leading University, Sylhet

September 2014 - April 2019